[{"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 1, "question": "Which of the following statements is not true?", "answer_choices": ["a. Water is polar.", "b. Water stabilizes temperature.", "c. Water is essential for life.", "d. Water is the most abundant atom in Earth\u2019s atmosphere."], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 2, "question": "Using a pH meter, you find the pH of an unknown solution to be 8.0. How would you describe this solution?", "answer_choices": ["a. weakly acidic", "b. strongly acidic", "c. weakly basic", "d. strongly basic"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 3, "question": "The pH of lemon juice is about 2.0, whereas tomato juice's pH is about 4.0. Approximately how much of an increase in hydrogen ion concentration is there between tomato juice and lemon juice?", "answer_choices": ["a. 2 times", "b. 10 times", "c. 100 times", "d. 1000 times"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 4, "question": "An example of a monosaccharide is ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. fructose", "b. glucose", "c. galactose", "d. all of the above"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 5, "question": "Cellulose and starch are examples of ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. monosaccharides", "b. disaccharides", "c. lipids", "d. polysaccharides"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 6, "question": "Phospholipids are important components of __________.", "answer_choices": ["a. the plasma membrane of cells", "b. the ring structure of steroids", "c. the waxy covering on leaves", "d. the double bond in hydrocarbon chains"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 7, "question": "The monomers that make up proteins are called _________.", "answer_choices": ["a. nucleotides", "b. disaccharides", "c. amino acids", "d. chaperones"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 8, "question": "What two products result from photosynthesis?", "answer_choices": ["a. water and carbon dioxide", "b. water and oxygen", "c. glucose and oxygen", "d. glucose and carbon dioxide"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 9, "question": "Which statement about thylakoids in eukaryotes is not correct?", "answer_choices": ["a. Thylakoids are assembled into stacks.", "b. Thylakoids are located in mitochondria.", "c. The space between the stroma and the inner membrane of the chloroplast is called stroma.", "d. Thylakoids contain chlorophyll."], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 10, "question": "From where does a heterotroph directly obtain its energy?", "answer_choices": ["a. the sun", "b. the sun and eating other organisms", "c. eating other organisms", "d. simple chemicals in the environment"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 11, "question": "What is the energy of a photon first used to do in photosynthesis?", "answer_choices": ["a. split a water molecule", "b. energize an electron", "c. produce ATP", "d. synthesize glucose"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 12, "question": "Which molecule absorbs the energy of a photon in photosynthesis?", "answer_choices": ["a. ATP", "b. glucose", "c. chlorophyll", "d. water"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 13, "question": "Plants produce oxygen when they photosynthesize. Where does the oxygen come from?", "answer_choices": ["a. splitting water molecules", "b. ATP synthesis", "c. the electron transport chain", "d. chlorophyll"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 14, "question": "Which color(s) of light does chlorophyll a reflect?", "answer_choices": ["a. red and blue", "b. green", "c. red", "d. blue"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 15, "question": "Where in plant cells does the Calvin cycle take place?", "answer_choices": ["a. thylakoid membrane", "b. thylakoid space", "c. stroma", "d. granum"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 16, "question": "Which statement correctly describes carbon fixation?", "answer_choices": ["a. the conversion of CO2 to an organic compound", "b. the use of RuBisCO, CO2, and RuBP to form 3-PGA", "c. the production of carbohydrate molecules from G3P", "d. the formation of RuBP from G3P molecules"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 17, "question": "What is the molecule that leaves the Calvin cycle to be converted into glucose?", "answer_choices": ["a. ADP", "b. G3P", "c. RuBP", "d. 3-PGA"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 18, "question": "Which of the following is not an example of an energy transformation?", "answer_choices": ["a. Heating up dinner in a microwave", "b. Solar panels at work", "c. Using sunlight to make glucose", "d. None of the above"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 19, "question": "Which of the following is not true about enzymes?", "answer_choices": ["a. They are consumed by the reactions they catalyze.", "b. They are usually made of amino acids.", "c. They lower the activation energy of chemical reactions.", "d. Each one is specific to the particular substrate"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 20, "question": "Energy is stored long-term in the bonds of _____ and used short-term to perform work from a(n) _____ molecule.", "answer_choices": ["a. ATP : glucose", "b. an anabolic molecule : catabolic molecule", "c. glucose : ATP", "d. a catabolic molecule : anabolic molecule"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 21, "question": "The energy currency used by cells is _____.", "answer_choices": ["a. ATP", "b. ADP", "c. AMP", "d. adenosine"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 22, "question": "The glucose that enters the glycolysis pathway is split into two molecules of _________.", "answer_choices": ["a. ATP", "b. phosphate", "c. NADH", "d. pyruvate"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 23, "question": "What do the electrons added to NAD+ during the citric acid cycle do in aerobic respiration?", "answer_choices": ["a. They become part of a fermentation pathway.", "b. They go to another pathway for ATP production.", "c. They energize the entry of the acetyl group into the citric acid cycle.", "d. They are converted into NADP."], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 24, "question": "Chemiosmosis involves", "answer_choices": ["a. the movement of electrons across the cell membrane", "b. the movement of hydrogen atoms across a mitochondrial membrane", "c. the movement of hydrogen ions across a mitochondrial membrane", "d. the movement of glucose through the cell membrane"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "biochemistry", "question_num": 25, "question": "Which of the following fermentation methods can occur in animal skeletal muscles?", "answer_choices": ["a. lactic acid fermentation", "b. alcohol fermentation", "c. mixed acid fermentation", "d. propionic fermentation"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "cells", "question_num": 1, "question": "When viewing a specimen through a light microscope, scientists use _________ to distinguish the individual components of cells.", "answer_choices": ["a. a beam of electrons", "b. radioactive isotopes", "c. special stains", "d. high temperatures"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "cells", "question_num": 2, "question": "The ___________ is the basic unit of life.", "answer_choices": ["a. organism", "b. cell", "c. tissue", "d. organ"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "cells", "question_num": 3, "question": "Which of these do all prokaryotes and eukaryotes share?", "answer_choices": ["a. nuclear envelope", "b. cell walls", "c. membrane-bound organelles", "d. plasma membrane"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "cells", "question_num": 4, "question": "Which of the following is found both in eukaryotic and prokaryotic cells?", "answer_choices": ["a. nucleus", "b. mitochondrion", "c. vacuole", "d. ribosome"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "cells", "question_num": 5, "question": "Which of the following is not involved in the synthesis or transport of proteins?", "answer_choices": ["a. mitochondrion", "b. Golgi apparatus", "c. endoplasmic reticulum", "d. ribosome"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "cells", "question_num": 6, "question": "The tails of the phospholipids of the plasma membrane are composed of _____ and are _______?", "answer_choices": ["a. phosphate groups; hydrophobic", "b. fatty acid groups; hydrophilic", "c. phosphate groups; hydrophilic", "d. fatty acid groups; hydrophobic"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "cells", "question_num": 7, "question": "Water is used to dissolve a solute in a glass container. Water molecules move via osmosis _________.", "answer_choices": ["a. throughout the cytoplasm", "b. from an area with a high concentration of other solutes to a lower one", "c. from an area with a low concentration of solutes to an area with a higher one", "d. from an area with a low concentration of water to one of higher concentration"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "cells", "question_num": 8, "question": "The principal force driving movement in diffusion is __________.", "answer_choices": ["a. temperature", "b. particle size", "c. concentration gradient", "d. membrane surface area"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "cells", "question_num": 9, "question": "A diploid cell has ________ the number of chromosomes as a haploid cell.", "answer_choices": ["a. one-fourth", "b. one-half", "c. twice", "d. four times"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "cells", "question_num": 10, "question": "An organism\u2019s traits are determined by the specific combination of inherited ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. cells", "b. genes", "c. proteins", "d. cholesterol"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "cells", "question_num": 11, "question": "Chromosomes are duplicated during what portion of the cell cycle?", "answer_choices": ["a. G1 phase", "b. S phase", "c. prophase", "d. prometaphase"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "cells", "question_num": 12, "question": "Separation of the sister chromatids is a characteristic of which stage of mitosis?", "answer_choices": ["a. prometaphase", "b. metaphase", "c. anaphase", "d. telophase"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "cells", "question_num": 13, "question": "The individual chromosomes start becoming visible with a light microscope during which stage of mitosis?", "answer_choices": ["a. prophase", "b. prometaphase", "c. metaphase", "d. anaphase"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "cells", "question_num": 14, "question": "What is necessary for a cell to pass the G2 checkpoint?", "answer_choices": ["a. cell has reached a sufficient size", "b. an adequate stockpile of nucleotides", "c. accurate and complete DNA replication", "d. proper attachment of mitotic spindle fibers to kinetochores"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "cells", "question_num": 15, "question": "________ are changes to the nucleotides in a segment of DNA that codes for a protein.", "answer_choices": ["a. Proto-oncogenes", "b. Tumor suppressor genes", "c. Gene mutations", "d. Negative regulators"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "cells", "question_num": 16, "question": "A gene that codes for a positive cell cycle regulator is called a(n) ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. kinase inhibitor", "b. tumor suppressor gene", "c. proto-oncogene", "d. p53"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "cells", "question_num": 17, "question": "Which event below is present in binary fission or the preparation for binary fission?", "answer_choices": ["a. Replicating membrane-bound organelles", "b. DNA duplication", "c. mitosis", "d. Attaching spindle fibers to kinetochores"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 1, "question": "What is a likely evolutionary advantage of sexual reproduction over asexual reproduction?", "answer_choices": ["a. sexual reproduction involves fewer steps", "b. less chance of using up the resources in a given environment", "c. sexual reproduction results in greater variation in the offspring", "d. sexual reproduction is more cost-effective"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 2, "question": "Which type of life cycle has both a haploid and diploid multicellular stage?", "answer_choices": ["a. an asexual life cycle", "b. diploid-dominant", "c. haploid-dominant", "d. alternation of generations"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 3, "question": "Which event leads to a diploid cell in a life cycle?", "answer_choices": ["a. meiosis", "b. fertilization", "c. alternation of generations", "d. mutation"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 4, "question": "Meiosis produces ________ daughter cells.", "answer_choices": ["a. two haploid", "b. two diploid", "c. four haploid", "d. four diploid"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 5, "question": "At which stage of meiosis are sister chromatids separated from each other?", "answer_choices": ["a. prophase I", "b. prophase II", "c. anaphase I", "d. anaphase II"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 6, "question": "If a muscle cell of a typical organism has 32 chromosomes, how many chromosomes will be in a gamete of that same organism?", "answer_choices": ["a. 8", "b. 16", "c. 32", "d. 64"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 7, "question": "The genotype XXY corresponds to:", "answer_choices": ["a. Klinefelter syndrome", "b. Turner syndrome", "c. Triplo-X", "d. Jacob syndrome"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 8, "question": "Imagine that you are performing a cross involving seed color in garden pea plants. What traits would you expect to observe in the F1 offspring if you cross true-breeding parents with green seeds and true-breeding parents with yellow seeds? Yellow seed color is dominant over green.", "answer_choices": ["a. only yellow-green seeds", "b. only yellow seeds", "c. 1:1 yellow seeds:green seeds", "d. 1:3 green seeds:yellow seeds"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 9, "question": "Imagine that you are performing a cross involving seed texture in garden pea plants. You cross true-breeding round and wrinkled parents to obtain F1 offspring. You then self-cross the individuals from the F1 generation. Which of the following experimental results are closest to what you expect in the F2 progeny? Round is dominant over wrinkled.", "answer_choices": ["a. 810 round seeds", "b. 810 wrinkled seeds", "c. 405:395 round seeds:wrinkled seeds", "d. 610:190 round seeds:wrinkled seeds"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 10, "question": "The observable traits expressed by an organism are described as its ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. phenotype", "b. genotype", "c. alleles", "d. zygote"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 11, "question": "A recessive trait will be observed in individuals that are ________ for that trait.", "answer_choices": ["a. heterozygous", "b. homozygous or heterozygous", "c. homozygous", "d. diploid"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 12, "question": "What are the types of gametes that can be produced by an individual with the genotype AaBb ?", "answer_choices": ["a. Aa, Bb", "b. AA , aa, BB , bb", "c. AB , Ab , aB , ab", "d. AB , ab"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 13, "question": "What is the reason for doing a test cross?", "answer_choices": ["a. to identify heterozygous individuals with the dominant phenotype", "b. to determine which allele is dominant and which is recessive", "c. to identify homozygous recessive individuals in the F2", "d. to determine if two genes assort independently"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 14, "question": "If true-breeding black mice and true-breeding white mice are mated and the result is all gray offspring, what inheritance pattern would this be indicative of?", "answer_choices": ["a. dominance", "b. codominance", "c. multiple alleles", "d. incomplete dominance"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 15, "question": "In a cross between a homozygous red-eyed female fruit fly and a white-eyed male fruit fly, what is the expected outcome? Red-eye color is dominant over white-eye color.", "answer_choices": ["a. all white-eyed male offspring", "b. all white-eyed female offspring", "c. all red-eyed offspring", "d. half white-eyed male offspring"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 16, "question": "When a population has a gene with four alleles circulating, how many possible genotypes are there?", "answer_choices": ["a. 3", "b. 6", "c. 10", "d. 16"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 17, "question": "In which group is parthenogenesis a normal event?", "answer_choices": ["a. chickens", "b. bees", "c. rabbits", "d. sea stars"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 18, "question": "Genetically unique individuals are produced through ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. sexual reproduction", "b. parthenogenesis", "c. budding", "d. fragmentation"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 19, "question": "The process of gastrulation forms the _______.", "answer_choices": ["a. blastula", "b. zygote", "c. organs", "d. germ layers"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 20, "question": "Which of the following gives rise to the skin cells?", "answer_choices": ["a. ectoderm", "b. endoderm", "c. mesoderm", "d. none of the above"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 21, "question": "Which human organ has an endometrial lining that will support a developing baby?", "answer_choices": ["a. labia minora", "b. breast", "c. ovaries", "d. uterus"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 22, "question": "Which hormone causes FSH and LH to be released?", "answer_choices": ["a. testosterone", "b. estrogen", "c. GnRH", "d. progesterone"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 23, "question": "Nutrient and waste requirements for the developing fetus are handled during the first few weeks by ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. the placenta", "b. diffusion through the endometrium", "c. the chorion", "d. the blastocyst"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "reproduction", "question_num": 24, "question": "Which hormone is primarily responsible for the contractions during labor?", "answer_choices": ["a. oxytocin", "b. estrogen", "c. beta-HCG", "d. progesterone"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "genetics", "question_num": 1, "question": "Which of the following does cytosine pair with?", "answer_choices": ["a. guanine", "b. thymine", "c. adenine", "d. a purine"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "genetics", "question_num": 2, "question": "Prokaryotes contain a ________chromosome, and eukaryotes contain ________ chromosomes.", "answer_choices": ["a. single-stranded circular; single-stranded linear", "b. single-stranded linear; single-stranded circular", "c. double-stranded circular; double-stranded linear", "d. double-stranded linear; double-stranded circular"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "genetics", "question_num": 3, "question": "DNA replicates by which of the following models?", "answer_choices": ["a. conservative", "b. semiconservative", "c. dispersive", "d. none of the above"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "genetics", "question_num": 4, "question": "The initial mechanism for repairing nucleotide errors in DNA is ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. mismatch repair", "b. chromosomal duplication", "c. chromosomal inversion", "d. thymine dimers"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "genetics", "question_num": 5, "question": "A promoter is ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. a specific sequence of DNA nucleotides", "b. a specific sequence of RNA nucleotides", "c. a protein that binds to DNA", "d. an enzyme that synthesizes RNA"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "genetics", "question_num": 6, "question": "Portions of eukaryotic mRNA sequence that are removed during RNA processing are ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. exons", "b. caps", "c. poly-A tails", "d. introns"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "genetics", "question_num": 7, "question": "The rRNA components of eukaryotic ribosomes are synthesized in the ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. cytoplasm", "b. ribosome", "c. nucleolus", "d. endoplasmic reticulum"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "genetics", "question_num": 8, "question": "How long would the peptide be that is translated from this mRNA sequence: 5'-AUGGGCUACCGAUAA-3'?", "answer_choices": ["a. 0", "b. 2", "c. 3", "d. 4"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "genetics", "question_num": 9, "question": "Control of gene expression in eukaryotic cells occurs at which level(s)?", "answer_choices": ["a. only the transcriptional level", "b. epigenetic and transcriptional levels", "c. epigenetic, transcriptional, and translational levels", "d. epigenetic, transcriptional, post-transcriptional, translational, and post-translational levels"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "genetics", "question_num": 10, "question": "Post-translational control refers to:", "answer_choices": ["a. regulation of gene expression after transcription", "b. regulation of gene expression after translation", "c. control of epigenetic activation", "d. period between transcription and translation"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "genetics", "question_num": 11, "question": "In gel electrophoresis of DNA, the different bands in the final gel form because the DNA molecules ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. are from different organisms", "b. have different lengths", "c. have different nucleotide compositions", "d. have different genes"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "genetics", "question_num": 12, "question": "In the reproductive cloning of an animal, the genome of the cloned individual comes from ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. a sperm cell", "b. an egg cell", "c. any gamete cell", "d. a body cell"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "genetics", "question_num": 13, "question": "What carries a gene from one organism into a bacteria cell?", "answer_choices": ["a. a plasmid", "b. an electrophoresis gel", "c. a restriction enzyme", "d. polymerase chain reaction"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "genetics", "question_num": 14, "question": "What is a genetically modified organism (GMO)?", "answer_choices": ["a. a plant with certain genes removed", "b. an organism with an artificially altered genome", "c. a hybrid organism", "d. any agricultural organism produced by breeding or biotechnology"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "genetics", "question_num": 15, "question": "What is the most challenging issue facing genome sequencing?", "answer_choices": ["a. the development of fast and accurate sequencing techniques", "b. the ethics of using information from genomes at the individual level", "c. the availability and stability of DNA", "d. all of the above"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "genetics", "question_num": 16, "question": "Genomics can be used in agriculture to:", "answer_choices": ["a. generate new hybrid strains", "b. improve disease resistance", "c. improve yield", "d. all of the above"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "evolution", "question_num": 1, "question": "Which scientific concept did Charles Darwin and Alfred Wallace independently discover?", "answer_choices": ["a. mutation", "b. natural selection", "c. overbreeding", "d. sexual reproduction"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "evolution", "question_num": 2, "question": "Which of the following situations demonstrate the concept of \u201csurvival of the fittest\u201d?", "answer_choices": ["a. The seeds of two plants land near each other and one grows larger than the other.", "b. Two types of fish eat the same kind of food, and one is better able to gather food than the other.", "c. Male lions compete for the right to mate with females, with only one possible winner.", "d. all of the above"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "evolution", "question_num": 3, "question": "Population genetics is the study of ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. how allele frequencies in a population change over time", "b. populations of cells in an individual", "c. the rate of population growth", "d. how genes affect embryological development"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "evolution", "question_num": 4, "question": "Gal\u00e1pagos medium ground finches are found on Santa Cruz and San Crist\u00f3bal islands, which are separated by about 100 km of ocean. Occasionally, individuals from either island fly to the other island to stay. This can alter the allele frequencies of the population through which of the following mechanisms?", "answer_choices": ["a. natural selection", "b. genetic drift", "c. gene flow", "d. mutation"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "evolution", "question_num": 5, "question": "In which of the following pairs do both evolutionary processes introduce new genetic variation into a population?", "answer_choices": ["a. natural selection and genetic drift", "b. mutation and gene flow", "c. natural selection and gene flow", "d. gene flow and genetic drift"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "evolution", "question_num": 6, "question": "The wing of a bird and the arm of a human are examples of ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. vestigial structures", "b. molecular structures", "c. homologous structures", "d. analogous structures"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "evolution", "question_num": 7, "question": "The fact that DNA sequences are more similar in more closely related organisms is evidence of what?", "answer_choices": ["a. optimal design in organisms", "b. adaptation", "c. mutation", "d. descent with modification"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "evolution", "question_num": 8, "question": "Which situation would most likely lead to allopatric speciation?", "answer_choices": ["a. A flood separates members of a population into two separate populations.", "b. A storm causes several large trees to fall down.", "c. A mutation causes a new trait to develop.", "d. An injury causes an organism to seek out a new food source."], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "evolution", "question_num": 9, "question": "Which variable increases the likelihood of allopatric speciation taking place more quickly?", "answer_choices": ["a. lower rate of mutation", "b. longer distance between divided groups", "c. increased instances of hybrid formation", "d. equivalent numbers of individuals in each population"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "evolution", "question_num": 10, "question": "What is a phylogeny a description of?", "answer_choices": ["a. mutations", "b. DNA", "c. evolutionary history", "d. organisms on Earth"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "evolution", "question_num": 11, "question": "Which best describes the relationship between chimpanzees and humans?", "answer_choices": ["a. chimpanzees evolved from humans", "b. humans evolved from chimpanzees", "c. chimpanzees and humans evolved from a\ncommon ancestor", "d. chimpanzees and humans belong to the same species"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "evolution", "question_num": 12, "question": "Which best describes a branch point in a phylogenetic tree?", "answer_choices": ["a. a hypothesis", "b. new lineage", "c. hybridization", "d. a mating"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "evolution", "question_num": 13, "question": "What is true about organisms that are a part of the same clade?", "answer_choices": ["a. They all share the same basic characteristics.", "b. They evolved from a shared ancestor.", "c. They all are on the same tree.", "d. They have identical phylogenies."], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "evolution", "question_num": 14, "question": "A monophyletic group is a ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. phylogenetic tree", "b. shared derived trait", "c. character state", "d. clade"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 1, "question": "When faced with a sudden drop in environmental temperature, an endothermic animal will react in which of the following manner?", "answer_choices": ["a. experience a drop in its body temperature", "b. wait to see if it goes lower", "c. increase muscle activity to generate heat", "d. add fur or fat to increase insulation"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 2, "question": "How are wastes carried to the kidney for removal?", "answer_choices": ["a. in cells", "b. in the urine", "c. in blood", "d. in lymphatic fluid"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 3, "question": "What is the cause of a fever of 38.3 \u00b0C (101 \u00b0F)?", "answer_choices": ["a. too much heat produced by the body", "b. upward adjustment of the body temperature set point", "c. inadequate cooling mechanisms in the body", "d. the heat directly released from the process of viral replication"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 4, "question": "Where does the majority of fat digestion take place?", "answer_choices": ["a. mouth", "b. stomach", "c. small intestine", "d. large intestine"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 5, "question": "The bile from the liver is delivered to the ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. stomach", "b. liver", "c. small intestine", "d. colon"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 6, "question": "Which of the following statements is not true?", "answer_choices": ["a. Vitamins can serve as coenzymes.", "b. Cholesterol is an essential component in the plasma membrane in animal cells.", "c. Some amino acids can be synthesized by the body, while others need to be obtained from diet.", "d. Urea is excreted through the lungs."], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 7, "question": "The respiratory system ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. provides body tissues with oxygen", "b. provides body tissues with oxygen and carbon dioxide", "c. establishes how many breaths are taken per minute", "d. provides the body with carbon dioxide"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 8, "question": "Which is the order of airflow during inhalation?", "answer_choices": ["a. nasal cavity, trachea, larynx, bronchi, bronchioles, alveoli", "b. nasal cavity, trachea, larynx, bronchi, bronchioles, alveoli", "c. nasal cavity, larynx, trachea, bronchioles, bronchi, alveoli", "d. nasal cavity, larynx, trachea, bronchi, bronchioles, alveoli"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 9, "question": "Where does the right ventricle send blood?", "answer_choices": ["a. the head", "b. the upper body", "c. the lungs", "d. the lower body"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 10, "question": "During the systolic phase of the cardiac cycle, the heart is ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. contracting", "b. relaxing", "c. contracting and relaxing", "d. filling with blood"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 11, "question": "How do arteries differ from veins?", "answer_choices": ["a. Arteries have thicker wall layers to accommodate the higher blood pressure as blood travels through them.", "b. Arteries carry blood.", "c. Arteries have thinner wall layers and valves and move blood by the action of skeletal muscle.", "d. Arteries are thin walled and are used for gas exchange."], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 12, "question": "Most of the hormones produced by the anterior pituitary perform what function?", "answer_choices": ["a. regulate growth", "b. regulate the sleep cycle", "c. regulate production of other hormones", "d. regulate blood volume and blood pressure"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 13, "question": "Which endocrine glands are located at the kidneys?", "answer_choices": ["a. thyroid glands", "b. pituitary glands", "c. adrenal glands", "d. gonads"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 14, "question": "Which component is responsible for initially stimulating a muscle contraction?", "answer_choices": ["a. proteins", "b. electrochemical signals", "c. plasma membranes", "d. striations"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 15, "question": "Neurons contain _________, which can receive signals from other neurons.", "answer_choices": ["a. axons", "b. mitochondria", "c. dendrites", "d. Golgi bodies"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 16, "question": "The part of the brain that is responsible for coordination during movement is the ______.", "answer_choices": ["a. limbic system", "b. thalamus", "c. cerebellum", "d. parietal lobe"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 17, "question": "Which statement is true?", "answer_choices": ["a. A virion contains DNA and RNA.", "b. Viruses are not cellular.", "c. Viruses replicate outside of the cell.", "d. Most viruses are easily visualized with a light microscope."], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 18, "question": "Viral ________ plays a role in attaching a virion to the host cell.", "answer_choices": ["a. core", "b. capsid", "c. envelope", "d. both b and c"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 19, "question": "Which statement is true of viral replication?", "answer_choices": ["a. In the process of apoptosis, the cell survives.", "b. During attachment, the virus attaches at specific sites on the cell surface.", "c. The viral capsid helps the host cell produce more copies of the viral genome.", "d. mRNA works outside of the host cell to produce enzymes and proteins."], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 20, "question": "Although interferons have several effects, they are particularly useful against infections with which type of pathogen?", "answer_choices": ["a. bacteria", "b. viruses", "c. fungi", "d. helminths"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 21, "question": "Which innate immune system component uses MHC class I molecules on infected cells to trigger apoptosis?", "answer_choices": ["a. red blood cells", "b. B cells", "c. natural killer cells", "d. interferon"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 22, "question": "The humoral immune response depends on which cells?", "answer_choices": ["a. cytotoxic T cells", "b. B cells only", "c. B and helper T cells", "d. cytotoxic T and helper T cells"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 23, "question": "The fact that the body does not normally mount an immune response to the molecules in food is an example of _______.", "answer_choices": ["a. secondary immune response", "b. immunological memory", "c. immune tolerance", "d. passive immunity"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 24, "question": "Allergy to pollen is classified as ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. an autoimmune reaction", "b. immunodeficiency", "c. delayed hypersensitivity", "d. immediate hypersensitivity"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "human body systems", "question_num": 25, "question": "Autoantibodies are probably involved in ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. reactions to poison ivy", "b. pollen allergies", "c. systemic lupus erythematosus", "d. HIV"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 1, "question": "Which of the following methods will provide information to an ecologist about both the size and density of an animal population in an area of a specific size?", "answer_choices": ["a. mark and recapture", "b. mark and release", "c. quadrat", "d. life table"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 2, "question": "Human populations have which type of survivorship curve?", "answer_choices": ["a. Type I", "b. Type II", "c. Type III", "d. Type IV"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 3, "question": "Species with limited resources usually exhibit a(n) ________ growth curve.", "answer_choices": ["a. logistic", "b. logical", "c. experimental", "d. exponential"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 4, "question": "The largest population size of a species capable of being supported by the environment is called its ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. limit", "b. carrying capacity", "c. biotic potential", "d. logistic growth pattern"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 5, "question": "Species that have many offspring at one time are usually:", "answer_choices": ["a. r-selected", "b. K -selected", "c. both r- and K -selected", "d. not selected"], "correct_answer": "a"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 6, "question": "A forest fire is an example of ________ regulation.", "answer_choices": ["a. population density-dependent", "b. population density-independent", "c. r-selected", "d. K -selected"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 7, "question": "Which of the following is not a way that humans have increased the human population?", "answer_choices": ["a. agriculture", "b. using large amounts of natural resources", "c. domestication of animals", "d. flying to the moon"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 8, "question": "The first species to live on new land, such as that formed from volcanic lava, are called________.", "answer_choices": ["a. climax community", "b. keystone species", "c. foundation species", "d. pioneer species"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 9, "question": "A symbiotic relationship where both of the co-existing species benefit from the interaction is called ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. commensalism", "b. parasitism", "c. mutualism", "d. kinship"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 10, "question": "When an invasive species alters the community structure it is introduced to, what can the consequence be?", "answer_choices": ["a. reduced population of keystone species", "b. reduced predation on some native species", "c. increased predation on some native species", "d. all of the above"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 11, "question": "The producer in an ocean food web is most likely to be which of the following?", "answer_choices": ["a. plant", "b. animal", "c. fungi", "d. plankton"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 12, "question": "Which term describes the process whereby toxic substances increase along trophic levels of an ecosystem?", "answer_choices": ["a. biomassification", "b. biomagnification", "c. bioentropy", "d. heterotrophy"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 13, "question": "The majority of the water found on Earth is:", "answer_choices": ["a. ice", "b. water vapor", "c. fresh water", "d. salt water"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 14, "question": "The process whereby oxygen is depleted by the growth of microorganisms due to excess nutrients in aquatic systems is called ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. dead zoning", "b. eutrophication", "c. retrophication", "d. depletion"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 15, "question": "Which of the following biomes is characterized by abundant water resources?", "answer_choices": ["a. deserts", "b. boreal forests", "c. savanna", "d. tropical wet forests"], "correct_answer": "d"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 16, "question": "Why is the tundra treeless?", "answer_choices": ["a. abundant source of water", "b. frozen ground", "c. warm weather", "d. too many fires"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 17, "question": "A key feature of estuaries is", "answer_choices": ["a. low light conditions and high productivity", "b. salt water and fresh water", "c. frequent algal blooms", "d. little or no vegetation"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 18, "question": "A secondary plant compound might be used for which of the following?", "answer_choices": ["a. a new crop variety", "b. a new drug", "c. a soil nutrient", "d. a crop pest"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 19, "question": "Pollination is an example of ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. a possible source of new drugs", "b. chemical diversity", "c. an ecosystem service", "d. crop pest control"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 20, "question": "Converting a prairie to a farm field is an example of ________.", "answer_choices": ["a. overharvesting", "b. habitat loss", "c. exotic species", "d. climate change"], "correct_answer": "b"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 21, "question": "Which risk may be a direct result of the pet trade?", "answer_choices": ["a. climate change", "b. habitat loss", "c. exotic species introduction", "d. pollution"], "correct_answer": "c"}, {"topic": "ecology", "question_num": 22, "question": "Which measures can protect biodiversity?", "answer_choices": ["a. legal protections", "b. conservation efforts", "c. restoration efforts", "d. all of the above"], "correct_answer": "d"}]